Before you create an initial product backlog, your team should have a shared vision of the product to develop
while the product vision is not an official artifact of scrum
it Can help set the goal that everybody can agrees on
Customer management, the product owner and developer
A good vision motivates the people working on the product
And it helps make scope decisions later on
What to put into the product and whatnot
That's why it is relevant for backlog management as well
As Ken Schwaber one of the fathers of Scrum once put it
The minimum plan necessary to start a scrum project
Consists of a vision and a product backlog
It's the product owner who leads the effort to come up with a product vision
It is created in close collaboration with the rest of the scrum team
And other stakeholders
Since this is a class about backlog management will focus on a very simple format for documenting the vision
The vision statement
A more sophisticated format
to Create a product vision
It's roman pichler product vision board
You find a link to it in the about section of the class
Let's say your company wants to develop an online portal for booking flights
Specifically targeted
Frequent flyers
Your vision statement Madrid
Frequent flyer
Fly often cheap and comfortable
In that statement you recognize Key properties of a vision
It should be short
That enables you to focus your development
You should point out for your Target user groups
In this case freak
Open Flyers
And it should state what users needs to have addressed
by the product
They want to fly
often cheap and comfortable
Once you have created a product Vision you should make it visible to the stakeholders for example printed out
Old and hang it in your team room
Once the stakeholders have agreed on a product vision
You can start creating an initial product backlog