What happens to the product backlog and Sprint planning
in Sprint planning at the beginning of the Sprint the product
owner discusses the stories at the top of the product backlog
with the developers the developers forecast
how many they are likely to get done during the Sprint
to be able to do the forecast the details
of the stories need to be understood well enough,
they should be the result of a negotiation between
the product owner and the developers and they should
be documented as acceptance criteria.
Here we are.
Also.
The story should be small so that the developers can
show the progress they made in Sprint review.
They should be around five to ten stories available for the
Sprint furthermore the team agrees on
an overarching goal for the Sprint the developers
to the design and agree on tasks to implement the stories.
Let's have a look at our top story from the example backlog
search single Airline when the product owner meets
the developers.
He has a lot of ideas.
The airline is fixed to United Airlines.
The frequent flyer can specify source and Target
airport day of departure and return how many adults
and children will fly and which class they will fly in the
product owner wants the source and Target airport is autocomplete
fields and the day of departure and return to be
picked from a calendar.
In the discussion with the developers it quickly turns out
that this story is too big for a two-week Sprint.
So the team starts to brainstorm.
What would be the simplest thing to do with the story?
Here's what the team agrees on the airline is
fixed to United Airlines same as before but
the source and Target airport are specified a simple text
Fields without autocomplete only the day of
departure can be specified.
So at first only single trips are possible.
The user needs to enter the date in a simple text field.
There's no calendar only one adult can fly
that is fixed in the class is fixed to coach.
On top of that the developers create a simple wire
frame to show what the page will look like.
Of course.
This story does not represent the final story that will
be delivered to end users.
It does not have to it's part of the iterative nature
of scrum to refine the work that has been done Sprint
by Sprint.
The team agrees on the Sprint goal to be able to book
a flight of a single airline to reach that goal
the team can stop discussing further details of the third
single Airline story.
Now,
this will be done in the future when the team has more knowledge
based on the implementation and feedback of the stakeholders
instead the team starts to discuss the other stories
needed to book a flight and defines acceptance criteria
for them as well.
But what about the original story the full version
of the search that will become clear when we look
at the story map that is updated by the team and
Sprint planning.
The product owner decides to put that story at
the very bottom of the map.
Maybe you think now why on Earth is dead remember
that the goal of the release was to ship a usable software
to test users to see if it's valuable the
product owner understands that to reach their goal.
The UI does not need to be polished or perfect.
So the story gets a lower priority its details
will be defined in a future Sprint when it will be implemented.
When the team has discussed the stories for the Sprint
the developers are confident that they are able to deliver
those stories.
So the pull the stories into the Sprint backlog.
They discuss the necessary development tasks to implement
the stories you can see them in the to do column.
The development tasks are different from the user tasks
in story mapping.
Our development has could be create controller
Class A create.
InDesign be or create see service.
And with that Sprint planning is complete.