What happens to the product backlog during the Sprint
as I said before, in Sprint planning the developers
put the top product backlog items to the Sprint backlog.
So they are removed from the product backlog, after
Sprint planning.
The so-called backlog refinement kicks in the
product owner talks to users developers and other
stakeholders about the future of the product.
The activities are similar to what we discussed for
Sprint planning with the differences that you
don't plan the current Sprint you plan one or
two sprints ahead.
So for example,
in order to satisfy the stakeholders the product
owner may decide to implement payment
with the different credit card first.
In Sprint review the developers demonstrate
the working software.
They built during the Sprint the product owner
the developers and other invited stakeholders
discuss what has been achieved and what should be done next
as a result of this the product backlog may change
for example in the first Sprint the developers
got the search done.
They also got the payment down because they could reuse
it from another product,
but they did not manage to Actually booked a flight
with another airline that turned out to be more
challenging than expected.
The product owner has a choice completely
discard the story or put it back in the backlog at
a certain position maybe with changed acceptance
criteria in the example.
She decides that booking a flight with another airline
should be implemented in the next Sprint as it
is part of the core functionality.
and that's what you do to the product backlog during
the sprint.