project managers and business analysts
play absolutely critical roles in
today's organizations
in today's project environment where
complexity
change and ambiguity are the norm
project managers and business analysts
must collaborate tightly and build deep
relationships with one another
to get great project results and better
business outcomes
hi i'm angela wick and welcome to this
course which focuses
on project manager and business analyst
collaboration
this course guides pms and bas through
the critical areas of role
overlap and collaboration points i
introduced two team members that paved
the way for each role through the course
pat the pm and bayley the ba will take
us through common scenarios and
areas where partnership between these
two roles is a must things like planning
and scope management
they will guide us through the key
mindsets and considerations such as
changing requirements and stakeholder
engagement
you will learn from pat and bailey that
this
deep collaboration will build trust with
stakeholders
foster an environment for stakeholder
engagement
and help the entire team focus on the
outcomes that matter with the project
are you ready to start your path towards
better collaboration
and discover a deeper relationship
between pms and bas
let's dive in