we can all cite why projects we've been
on have failed
and research studies give us many clues
as well
but have you ever really looked at how
the pm and ba
relationship could contribute to these
failures and possibly even prevent them
let's look at a few ideas
first lack of stakeholder engagement and
involvement
and this includes engaged sponsors
and sponsors having clear vision and
objectives
the ba and pm have key roles in helping
the leaders
take the vision and objectives and turn
them from
strategy to execution stakeholder
involvement at the leader
and contributor levels is key to making
the strategy
and vision a reality the pm
and ba are the team members that
interact with stakeholders and leaders
the most
throughout the project when both roles
are interacting with the same
stakeholders and
often there's a need to collaborate
tightly on these interactions
to keep stakeholder engagement high
these stakeholders typically have
full-time roles outside of the project
so keeping the engagement strong yet not
burdemsome
is a key element next changing
priorities is a key failure point
how teams handle changing priorities can
have a huge
impact on if value gets delivered on
projects
this value point also points back to
stakeholder involvement
the pm and ba are both heavily involved
in managing priorities with stakeholders
and influencing stakeholders on
prioritization
and last changing requirements
changing requirements can be a good
thing or a bad thing
embracing changing requirements can lead
to a competitive advantage if the
changes
are result of learning more about what
customers and users needs are
at the same time if the project can't
seem to deliver anything
due to starts and stops with constant
changes
this can lead to failure the pm
and ba collaborate heavily on helping
stakeholders and the team
identify and manage requirements into
pieces of work
these deliverables if not well defined
can be delivered in increments that make
requirements change less risky
while leveraging change for a
competitive advantage
pat the pm and bayley the ba start
getting into
deep discussions on what does success
mean on a project anyway
is it when a project is delivered on
schedule
within budget results in a working
product
or meets the business intent they
determine that the best approach for
them is to collaborate on defining
success for projects with stakeholders
the business intent may be to beat a
competitor to market while sacrificing
quality and cost time is most important
to success
or the product working at a determined
quality level with customer delight
may be far more important than cost and
schedule
most leaders want cost schedule and
quality while delighting the customer
but it's important to know which is
leading the success equation
pat and bailey have found that this has
dramatically changed how they work
and collaborate