many wonder if one person
can be both the project manager and the
ba on a project
it's an important question to ask and
there are many factors that go into the
answer
there are times when this can work and
also times
i wouldn't recommend it let's look at
the essence of what each role does
a project manager is responsible for
delivering the work of the project
this often includes defining the work
and delivering the work within a budget
and schedule
with agreed upon quality levels a
business analyst
is responsible for ensuring what the
project delivers
is valuable and meets the needs of the
business and customers
without one of these roles chaos can
break out
lackluster results can ensue or simply
the project fails
if a project has a pm and no ba
or no one performing the ba role or
perhaps the ba role isn't done well
the project is at a high risk of
building the wrong
thing this is realized when users get
the product
and react that it's not what they needed
often it's too late
and too much has been spent before
leaders realize
that there's been waste in building the
wrong thing
on the flip side if a project has a ba
and no pm or no one performing the pm
role
or the pm role isn't done well the
project has a high risk of running into
schedule and budget issues
and the analysis takes too much priority
over the budget and schedule
or potentially decision making is
impeded
by focus on other areas depending on the
project approach and methodology
various factors and roles can influence
these dynamics
each project is different and the
context can change
everything for example some projects
follow a traditional approach with
formal plans and formal documentation
and the size and complexity of the
project can be a big factor
the larger the project the more a pm
and or multiple bas are needed
if the project is quite small one person
may be able to play both roles
on projects using a more agile approach
the pm
role really depends on the enterprise
roles
and context and the ba rule typically
depends on the complexity
as well as the product owner's
availability and skill set
having both roles represented is
critical
and hopefully can lead to some healthy
conflict
when what needs to be built conflicts
with the budget
and schedule needs this is a healthy
conflict where both roles can balance
the decision-making process
and help business leaders make critical
decisions
this duo of PM and BA is an awesome duo
to provide projects with the balance to
succeed