many confuse the terms project and
product
is this something you've experienced too
project what's the difference a project
is a temporary initiative to create a
product
and a product is something that delivers
value
as the result of a project it's easy to
use them
interchangeably in conversation yet in
project work
it's important to differentiate the
focus of each of these
is different the product lives on
while the project is temporary the pm
focuses on the project and the ba
focuses on the product
let's look at pat the pm and bailey the
ba
pat the pm and bailey the ba are on a
project together
looking to transform their customer
relationship management processes
or crm for short and improve customer
relationships
the organization built a legacy system
years ago for crm
and it's no longer cost effective to
maintain
nor is it meeting business goals and
needs
they decided to invest in a new system
and determine that purchasing
rather than building software is the
approach to take
the project is the initiative to make
the change
it's temporary and has completion
criteria
the product is the system and process
that lives on
after the project is complete the
project creates the product
it's common that smaller projects or a
product team is formed
to enhance the product as needed
pat looks from the project perspective
and
bailey looks at the product point of
view for the crm project
this has pat looking at the vendor
management
resources budget schedule
and overall plans for the project
bailey's focus is on the groups that are
impacted
and how their usage and interaction with
the system changes
bailey is also looking at how any end
customer touch points may be impacted
bailly's focus is working with
stakeholders to understand how the new
crm
package works and what it takes to make
it work in their environment to serve
their operation and customers
collaboration between patent bailly is
critical
as they feed one another to get their
work accomplished
successfully bailey working to define
the product and its requirements
will run into scope questions and scope
questions
feed the estimates and schedule that
pat's working on
changing priorities means changes to
scope requirements
budget and schedule and an increase in
risk for the project
changing requirements involve both pat
and bailey
working together to ensure the right
expectations and value are delivered
pat and bailey work well together as a
team because they both
understand the difference between the
project and the product
and what it means to their roles and how
they work together
they're in constant communication on
areas where the project
and the product overlap and they play
off one another's work to get great
results
for stakeholders