Pat the PM and Bailey, the BA are about to
start a new project together.
They're working together to plan out key aspects
of the project.
And they have a sensitive stakeholder.
For a moment.
Let's imagine that we're that stakeholder,
Jennifer.
as Jennifer, you're a full time manager of
a payroll department, Your days are filled
managing a large staff vendors, technology
and payroll cycles.
You're dealing with expectations, regulatory
changes, taxation, operational quotas and
deadlines.
And your customers or employees to get payroll,
just want to be paid on time and paid correctly.
You're put on a new project that's looking
to improve the systems that make all this
payroll happen.
Suddenly, in addition to your normal and stressful
responsibilities as a payroll manager, you
get meeting invites from three or four
Different people on the project team, you
don't really know who they all are or their
roles, and the demands, emails and meetings
just keep coming.
You simply don't have time for all this nervous
space in your brain to keep any of it straight.
You've got a department to run.
Now, let's imagine it differently.
Instead, for the project.
you first meet Pat and Bailey.
They explain their roles as the pm and ba
how they work together.
And with you, they determine a schedule of
meetings and expectations that works for you.
You now know why it's important to go to certain
meetings and discuss with them what you actually
have time for.
Communications, emails, and meetings are coordinated
so that it makes sense to you in the team
and it's organized from your perspective.
This type of collaboration Pat and Bailey
demonstrate is not by accident.
When a pm and ba work together and managing
stakeholders, communications, risk and scope,
it builds trust, reduces risk and engages
stakeholders.
This leads to better quality products and
great relationships that ultimately leads
to getting the project done on time within
budget.
And while meeting the needs of stakeholders
and delivering value.
Many things go into successful projects.
And there is no doubt that collaboration is
at the top of the list.