project managers and business analysts are
like a dynamic duo.
A great relationship between the pm and ba
makes for promising project results.
But there's confusing overlap at times.
So what are the areas where these roles overlap
the most scoping and planning, communications,
stakeholder relationships and management,
and risk management?
Let's look at each area.
First scoping and planning.
Many PMS do some of this before a BA is assigned
on the project.
And since the BAs focus is the product in
defining what the product is in varying levels
of detail, it's imperative that the BA either
do the scoping, or clarify the scope of the
product from a functional and user point of
view.
Scope clarification leads to better planning
for the whole project team which results in
better detail requirements, better estimates
and involving the right stakeholders.
And this benefits everyone.
Next communications.
many team members and stakeholders get communications
from so many on the team.
And the pm and ba may be the most common offenders.
No really, communications are good, but great
communications are coordinated, collaborated
and make sense to the audience.
PMs and BAs work together to strategize key
messages for various team members and stakeholders
and work to communicate a consistent message
that uses the team and stakeholders time effectively.
Next to stakeholder relationships and management.
Together, PMs and BAs can create trusting
and engaging relationships with project stakeholders
when not collaborating on the relationships
often trust issues build and engagement drops
Creating a high risk for project failure.
And last is risk management.
Risk can come from many areas, and the pm
and ba typically have many of them covered.
What's important is that PMs and BAs work
together to discuss the risks and work through
the mitigation and response plans together.
BAs need to pay careful attention to the risks
to the user, and the customer experience and
processes, scope, stakeholders communication
and risk.
These are the key areas of overlap.
If you're thinking, wow, this means I spend
a lot of time with the pm or ba.
You're right on.
Yes, collaboration between these roles is
intense and all for good reason.