pat the pm is worried about the project
deadline
it's coming up quick and bailey is
concerned about the quality
requirements were rushed scope was added
along the way
and testing is showing lots of issues
that will impact the business teams and
customers if the team implements
try to take a rubber band and stretch it
three ways into a triangle
now if we pull one of the corners out
putting pressure on that corner what
happens to these other corners
they get stressed out and they might
break
the triple constraint of project
management works the same
cost schedule and scope is what the
triple constraint is made of
how this works is that if you increase
the need
or importance of one the others get
stressed
and need attention too so if we
increase the scope the cost and schedule
need to increase as well
makes sense right isn't it funny how
easy it is to say
yes to increasing one without planning
for the increase in the others
as easy as it is and as much as it seems
our leaders expect magic
it's detrimental to project success to
allow a pattern of thinking that one
doesn't impact the others
pat and bailey are in the heat of this
pat
concerned about missing the deadline and
bailey concerned about the quality due
to rushed requirements and added scope
project managers and bas collaborate
together with leaders to understand
which of the three triple constraint
areas are the most important
to meeting objectives and delivering
value
the pm and ba need to be in sync
together
with both the leaders and the team in
understanding which of the three will
lead decision making
this decision can impact strategy and
how well the project
executes on a leader's strategy so for
example
on a project implementing a new customer
billing system
an organization that leads with cost as
the driver
will sacrifice schedule and scope to
some degree to hit the cost objectives
and likewise if scope is prioritized
schedule and costs will not be optimized
as much
so which to prioritize depends on the
real business objectives
and in a perfect world all three are
balanced
let's say the customer experience is the
most important factor in making the
project successful
and if the customer experience with the
new billing system
isn't at a certain level the project
isn't even worth doing
then scope and quality need to lead over
cost and schedule
if we demand if at certain scope quality
all be important then the team needs to
understand minimums in each
area and if it's feasible what's
interesting to me
is that many teams think that cost and
schedule lead their projects
yet when i ask the leaders what they
think
they answer scope and quality and
customer experience
meaning they want the right thing to be
built at the right quality level
so it's important for pms and bas to
collaborate together with leaders
to get at the true drivers and
motivations of the project
keep success in plain view with the
triple constraint
by talking through which is leading and
how the project will manage
when the wrong one pulls the others
managing the triple constraint is a
great way for pms and bas to
anchor key collaboration points