So what does the ideal partnership for a project
manager and BA look like?
Well, I've been on a lot of projects as a
BA with great PM relationships.
And here's what it looked and felt like.
I typically touch base with the PM first thing
in the morning to see what's on her mind as
priorities for the day.
We discussed the meetings we have scheduled,
who the stakeholders are in those meetings
and the meeting goals, and we make decisions
on adjusting any meetings to make the stakeholder
interactions positive.
We also discussed the previous day's stakeholder
interactions and other updates from the last
day or so.
Throughout the day, we run into each other
a few times and see how we can support one
another with key messages to others and being
consistent in our actions and priorities.
It's also quite common for me as the BA to
have dialogue with stakeholders that could
introduce scope creep, scope, creep. is when
items get added to the scope without the right
governance around making sure that it's truly
the right scope to add.
It can easily happen in requirements discussions,
and it's something I like to talk to the PM
about as soon as I can.
I want to give her a heads up on that dialogue,
while I investigate the value, risk and impact
of any changes as well as the feasibility.
The PM can also help with discovering these
critical things.
And together, we can make sure the right decisions
are made.
I often grab coffee or lunch with a PM for
more casual dialogue, and time to reflect
on risks and stakeholder relationships.
This is where some really good insights come
in, as well as a deeper relationship between
the PM and myself.
I want her to know that I'm thinking about
things like how I'm approaching my work and
caring for the project as a whole.
I want to build Trust and transparency with
the PM.
So we can focus on leading and influencing
together as a team.
Think about how this might be different from
your PM BA relationship.
What can you do to improve your partnership?
The partnership between the PM and BA is one
that can literally be magical for the project.
A great partnership can build trust in the
team and stakeholders.
And my favorite part is that it's rewarding
and feels good to have a great partnership
on the job.