at the portfolio level pms
and bas are working to define projects
related to strategic goals of the
organization
and align the projects together as a
group of related projects
at times the intake of defects and
enhancements get integrated into these
portfolios as well
project and program managers are looking
at the budget and schedule linkages
as well as overall strategic alignment
of the project goals
bas are looking at strategic alignment
business architecture and the big
picture of who is impacted
and the value the groups need to get
from these projects
our team members pat the pm and bayley
the ba
may be assigned to work on the portfolio
level with other pms and bas
or as part of the intake process to
start up a large set of projects
some key tactical things that pat and
bailey collaborate on
are first defining the problem or
opportunity statement
they create a shared understanding
together with the leaders
on the problem or opportunity which
helps with strategic alignment
as they look at the portfolio of work
it also helps the team facilitate the
dialogue as to prioritizing the work
and defining the work into valuable
pieces to deliver
next they work together to define the
value proposition for the impacted
stakeholder groups
and not forgetting about the customer
they
think through each group and ask
research
and discover how the project benefits
the group
and next they determine measurable goals
and objectives to help
chart the course and keep scope tied and
aligned to measurable outcomes
it's not good enough to say we want to
improve the customer experience
we need to define more measurable
outcomes
like what part of the customer
experience or
what measurement of the customer
experience are we targeting to improve
and why also
they work together to define what
capabilities are missing to meet these
goals
this may include new innovations new
processes
new systems and new behaviors
it also may mean that new groups perform
new tasks
it may mean automation or the removal of
some capabilities
they focus capabilities back to how they
impact the customer's experience with
using
products and services and like you
they have seen far too many projects
that create strategically crafted
capabilities
at the expense of customers not happy
with the impact to their experience
another thing pat and bailey look at is
the feasibility of the approach
feasibility can be technical cost
related
schedule related and also about the
business design and people factors
truly challenging assumptions on what is
and is not
feasible really matters
regards to cost feasibility
organizations define this in various
ways
some organizations ask themselves how
much will it cost
and how much will i get in return and
some ask what am i willing to spend to
get this
done there are various methods
calculations and terms for this
things like return on investment net
present value
business case cost of delay
and weighted shortest job first
at a minimum i like to look at how the
project would
increase revenue reduce risk or reduce
cost
and then how much is the likely cost and
likely benefit a table like this can be
a simple way to view this
here we can see the range of cost
minimum likely and maximum
and the same range for benefit now how
much detail is behind this
is up to you the project manager and
sponsors
prioritizing the items in a portfolio is
the last piece of the equation
pat and bailey work together to help
business leaders make prioritization
decisions
by helping leaders participate in the
various activities we've discussed
the idea is to make decision making
easier and with higher quality decisions
it's about making priorities and
decisions flexible
by defining independent and valuable
pieces
that are not dependent on other projects
and this gives leaders the flexibility
to adapt as needed
pat and bailey are part of an
organization where bailey has an active
role in this process
since the intake process requires a lot
of analysis to make the right decisions
bailey's role is critical bailey helps
ensure
the organization is working on the right
stuff at the right time
working together on this with a blend of
skills pms
and bas bring to the table can benefit
portfolio planning in big ways
it can bring a powerful decision-making
process to strategic alignment
that can make all the difference
you