Scope is a big collaboration point for PMs
and BAs, I can't stress this enough, what
most teams don't realize is what scope actually
means.
Teams often focus on the project scope and
not enough on the product scope.
We have an intuitive idea from experience
and there are also ways to think about scope
that can help us work together to make scope
more clear, to manage.
Pat the PM and Bailey the BA think about scope
and five ways project scope.
Product scope.
And functional scope, technical scope and
organizational scope, they have learned that
a lot of teams are focused on the project
and technical scope and mistakenly neglecting
the product and functional scope.
The project scope, which includes the work
to be done and resources to do it, the tasks,
the people and organizations performing the
activities to complete the project.
Pat is focused on this scope, and Bailey provides
inputs from other scope areas that help Pat
with that project scope.
Next, the product scope, which is what the
project builds and can be looked at from a
functional and technical point of view.
Bailey is focused on the functional scope,
what features goals and functions the product,
service or system will provide by the end
of the project, and the technical scope is
about what technologies are impacted.
Pat and Bailey work together on this with
a technical lead.
The functional scope is where Bailey provides
a leadership role as input to pat managing
scope.
Overall as a whole, the functional scope provides
critical input to the other scope areas Pat
needs and Bailey analyses, defines and communicates
this to create a shared understanding, missing
functional scope, impact, schedule, resources
and budget.
Pat and bailey are tied together in this area
to ensure a smooth scope, understanding and
decision making.The organizational scope is
another area of scope that patent and Bailey
collaborate on, as it involves understanding
what locations, units and groups of the organization
are impacted.
Another big scope concept is scope creep,
and at times it's Pat's biggest fear.
Scope creep is when scope is added to the
deliverables, plans or promise to stakeholders
without truly planning the impacts on resources,
costs and schedule.
This can happen if the project approaches
scope creep as being a bad thing without prioritizing
what can be removed to accommodate the scope
change.
Scope creep can be Pat's nightmare and create
a lot of stress if not managed.
Bailey, the BA can easily and unknowingly
create scope creep in conversations with stakeholders.
Being aware of this dynamic and working with
Pat in these situations is critical.
Scope creep can also be a positive thing if
managed well between Pat and Bailey.
If a stakeholder discussion yields new features
that were not previously planned, there needs
to be an understanding of the value of the
feature in question and the priority of it.
If it truly will make or break the value delivered
and it's a top priority, then it should be
added to scope Pat , Bailey in the business,
leaders need to have dialoge to make a decision
on priorities, risk, budget and schedule.
It could mean scoping something else or increasing
the cost or even increasing the time to fit
it in.
The important part is that it's managed and
leveraged for value, not feared.
I've created a scoping checklist for PMs and
BAs to use in collaboration with one another.
This will help your team plan and manage scope.
Remember, collaborate closely and don't be
afraid of scope creep, embrace it and manage
it.