so how do pat the pm and bailey the ba
work together to plan and estimate
the ba is responsible for defining the
product
and the pm defines the project
the project delivers the product
how could anyone plan a project without
a great
understanding of the product well
depending how much the product has been
defined when the planning happens
planning can be impacted dramatically
in some ways i've always thought it was
silly to estimate and plan for
requirements
when the requirements are not yet known
at the same time with experience
we learned to work with ambiguity by
working in
layers and we also learned to plan to
replan as we learn
more and bailey and pat plan to replan
as they go to they realize that planning
with ambiguity
helps leaders make decisions and
re-planning
is expected so what is there to be
planned and estimated
and how do patent bailey collaborate on
this
first bailly and pat plan what the
actual
product is and understanding what
outcomes are expected
and for whom for some projects these are
backlog items releases
or iterations of a product
pat and bailey discover and communicate
the big picture of the product
and the upcoming pieces that will be in
the next focus area
pat needs to estimate and plan for
resources and with bailey's help
understands more about the product
bailey does planning related to
requirements and business analysis
process
and this planning informs pat on
estimates and dependencies for the
analysis pieces
and also has a critical role in
stakeholders
understanding what's expected of them
and when
bailey might have a ba plan with the
analysis deliverables
activities timelines and stakeholders
outlined
bailey may also have a requirements
management plan
showing how decisions and requirements
will be tracked and approved
bailey also has models that serve as
assets to the team
to show the product's scope context and
environment or ecosystem of the product
all these help inform the project plan
that pat is working on and all these are
great dialogue and collaboration points
for pat and bailey
they all tied together and need to be
aligned
together pat and bailey work in
leveraging their expertise and past
experiences in planning and estimating
pat and bailey also worked together on
complexity and impact assessments for
the project
together they look at the various
aspects of complexity
in how many areas and groups are
impacted
they look at the risk profile of the
project and how big of a change it is
for each group
this also informs the project plan and
risk planning
planning and estimating are key areas of
pm
and ba collaboration it's hard to
imagine a project being successful
without it