Requirements and analysis.
This is all on the BA. right.
Well while Bailey does own the requirements
process Pat the PM needs to be informed and
consulted on the plan.
The progress stakeholder interactions and
both need a collaborative understanding of
what the highest value requirements are.
Much of this is driven by prioritization knowing
which requirements are of the highest priority
brings Pat and Bailey's collaboration into
focus.
Pat is managing vendors planning resources
and facilitating the work activities of the
team.
If the highest priority requirements are not
clear the team is likely spending time on
things that may not matter during the requirements
and analysis activities.
It's important to bring Pat up to speed and
into the activities the important times Bailey
brings Pat in are the plan for requirements
and when it's changing and when new stakeholders
are needed.
Also when the analysis shows complexities
and risks to delivering the intended value
it's also important for Pat to understand
and weigh in on what will be documented for
requirements.
Some projects and teams use little documentation
due to a small work in progress and a small
team.
Other Teams require large amounts of documentation
and requirements due to various factors in
how the project is set up.
Bailey is as transparent as possible on the
status of the requirements activities as they
progress to keep patent formed.
They have learned through the years working
together to report status on activities and
towards completion of the milestones not completion
of a document Bailey has also learned to be
transparent about what requirements activities
are and has found this to be a critical thing
in building a trusting relationship with Pat
another area.
During the requirements and analysis activities
Pat and Bailey collaborate on is the approval
of requirements for some teams.
This happens with a decision maker and a verbal
approval and for other teams there is a lengthy
signoff process with multiple parties signing
off and formal approval processes.
Either way it's important for Pat and Bailey
to have a shared understanding of the process
and progress when analyzing requirements.
Bailey communicates to Pat what the highest
value requirements are this continues dialogue
between Pat and Bailey which ensures the right
focus areas are in view for both roles.
And when working on collaborating on requirements
it helps hugely when requirements are phrased
in business terminology and phrased in increments
of value they should be understandable from
a customer point of view and easy to understand
for the project manager and business leader.
This allows Pat Bailey and the business leaders
to discuss key requirements and decisions
requirements analysis is so important to projects
and bringing the PM into it at the appropriate
places.
Makes it even better.