during the build and testing activities
on projects
pat the pm and bailey the ba collaborate
to ensure the team has a shared
understanding
of what features and aspects of each
feature
are the highest priority and will be
most valuable to the users
in the organization first
let's look at the build activities which
is all about
collaborating with the developers on
their questions
and ensuring they have the right
priorities and shared understanding
here the intent of the requirements is
to be the focus
pat and bailey provide the delivery team
context of what the user's reason for
using the system and features are
pat and bailey want the team to see the
bigger picture of the user journey and
goals
and the developers want and need this
too
there are always questions about the
requirements and what's being built from
developers
and developers feel under pressure to
work fast
pat and bailey work together to provide
an environment of
trust and communications to the delivery
team
that fosters an openness to discuss the
what
and the why behind what's being built
much of this is already provided in the
requirements and dialogue that has
already taken place
and it's important to continue this
dialogue as well
the budget and schedule that pat cares
about is typically top of mind during
these activities
as the team looks towards implementation
so there can be a natural conflict on
the team
pat and bailey provide an environment to
not just meet deadlines
but to make sure the team builds what's
intended
it's also easy during these activities
to neglect focus on the value and
outcomes of what's being delivered
the team's understanding of what the
desired outcomes are
is where bailey plays a big role and pat
needs to support this as well bailey
also needs to support the budget and
schedule conditions the team is working
under
next are the testing activities and much
like development
there's a lot of pressure on the team to
meet deadlines
this means that the team needs to be
focused on the most
important areas and aspects that deliver
value
we can't test everything in every
possible scenario
so how does the team know where to focus
well bailey provides
critical context and dialogue for the
testing activities
to help the team focus on the right
areas to test
and collaborates with pat and the team
to make sure the schedule and budget
are used in the right places
both the ba and pm play critical roles
in communicating
and supporting the shared understanding
together
and this makes the build and testing
phases go much
smoother
you