so requirements are done
now what does implementation have to do
with the ba
and pm partnership bailey the ba
has the requirements done helped with
development and testing
so what's next collaborating on
implementation starts
long before prepping for the go live day
activities
and the key areas where pat the pm and
bayley the ba collaborate
are the transition requirements and
change readiness
let's start with transition requirements
these are the requirements that define
what it takes to transition from the old
to the new solution
and bailey thinks about them often
they're things like
what data needs to be brought from the
old to the new solution
so that it works as intended for users
and customers
an example of this is customer data
if a new system is implemented for an
organization
and none of the customer data is
transitioned to the new system
then when i interact as a customer the
new system may not know who i am
or my history this means customer
service nor myself
has information about me as a customer
it may seem
far-reaching to think this gets
forgotten or not done well
but it happens more often than you think
or the team thinks it's taken care of
but the customer experience
shows another view related to this
is other data migrations of work in
progress
things like current orders and status
data
another area of transition and
implementation preparation
patent bailey collaborate on is change
readiness
this includes things like training the
users
communicating the changes to each group
impacted
and evaluating if those impacted are
ready to make the change without adverse
impact
to the organization or customers
and last the go no go decision
facilitating the decision among
stakeholders of
readiness to deploy is a partnership
activity between pat and bailey
both pat and bailey have relationships
with the stakeholders
and have perspectives on the end
customer points of view
pat is looking closely at the triple
constraint
while bailly is analyzing the experience
and impacts to user groups in the
customer
all these pieces need to be taken into
account in these critical decisions
and moments of implementation
pat and bailey makes sure all the angles
are considered in the decision making
and both pat and bailey have a powerful
lens to provide
value together as the project heads
towards hopefully
a rewarding implementation