Pat, the PM feels like sometimes it takes
saying something 20 times before it's heard,
and Pat leverages Bailey, the BA, to help
communicate some of these messages to the
key is communicating when the listener is
receptive.
And that's hard to pinpoint.
So it's a good strategy.
Many use to communicate things many times
in many different ways and also using others
to help communicate the same message.
This is true on projects as well as patent
collaborate to bring key messages to stakeholders
and user groups impacted by the project, and
this communication can be simply tactical
or quite strategic as well.
This requires a lot of communication between
Pat and Bailey themselves.
Pat and Bailey mainly collaborate to communicate
to the team, to create transparency and inspire
engagement with the team.
They communicate things like a shared understanding
of what requirements and intent.
And what's the highest priorities the team
is working on the timelines and also a lot
of detailed conversations.
Pat and Bailey collaborate to look at ensuring
a consistent message is being communicated
to each person or group.
They also listen intently to stakeholder's,
watch other's body language and watch their
own when communicating and sharing our learnings
with one another.
This allows them to connect better with stakeholders,
build trust and create better relationships
with the team and stakeholders.I resonate
with this.
I often find myself sharing with the PM the
various discussions that came up and the key
points and planning to have.
Then she can check in with the same stakeholder
and seek to understand if the message was
successful.
Often there are opportunities to create another
communication and maybe a different manner
with different words to try again to communicate
the same thing.
This is a critical part of a PM and BA collaboration.
Besides working with stakeholders, PMS and
BAs communicate a lot with each other.
It's important to ensure as much transparency
in our work as possible to make this communication
go smoothly.
Transparency and things like what am I working
on?
What are my priorities today, who I plan to
interact with and the key messages that we
need to collaborate on?
Communicating together to help get project
activities completed and influence others
is what it's all about, you can choose to
communicate tactically or strategically.
Strategic communication is all about thinking
one step ahead with what others need and working
together on key messages that make all the
difference.