When Bailey the BA first started out, not
much attention was given to risk management
and many boys feel the same, it's a PM thing.
Bailey found working closely with the PM that
the payroll had a lot to do with risk management
and learned how to become an integral part
of it.
Bailey found three main areas of risk that
helped a lot when collaborating with Pat stakeholder
involvement, the risk of building the wrong
thing and risk schedule.
Many studies have shown that a top risk for
projects is inadequate requirements.
And they also show that the number one risk
to high quality requirements is lack of stakeholder
involvement in this course.
We've talked a lot about stakeholders and
how Pat and Bailey work together in communicating
and managing stakeholder relationships.
This comes full circle with risk management
as they work together to identify and mitigate
or manage the risks of stakeholders who are
not engaged or not as engaged as we need them
to be.
Have you ever had a challenge getting stakeholders
time?
I know quite the question.
I'm sure you have.
The next big risk and what I'm quite passionate
about is the risk of building the wrong thing.
This also includes the risk of simply not
delivering any value to users and to customers
with what we build, even if it's exactly what
they asked for together.Pat and Bailey analyze
context stakeholders and the organization
to ensure what's being built matters.
And it's the right thing to build Pat and
Bailey's share learnings, bring curiosity
to the team and facilitate shared understanding
with the team on the vision and the why behind
the project.
The team understanding the intent of what's
needed and why it's needed is so critical.
The last crucial area of risk to collaborate
on is schedule.
The work Bailey does can have a big impact
on the schedule.
Pat is working hard to manage.
Both must be transparent and their activities
and status, including impediments.
I also want to talk a little bit about assumptions.
Both Pat and Bailey elicit and track assumptions
and assumptions, if not true, become big risks.
So like other areas, they make these transparent
and talk about them together to collaborate.
Overall, PM's and BAs work together to draw
on each other's expertise and experience to
ensure that risks are well understood and
so that the team and the leaders can make
good decisions.