Pat, the PM and Bailey, the BA are working
on their CRM project, and they know that stakeholder
management will be a big factor in their success.
They're especially concerned about the project
due to the stakeholder being extremely busy
and not having time for the project, yet this
project is looking to change a lot about what
these stakeholder groups do.
Our stakeholders have full time jobs, and
the project is usually a side job for them.
Imagine having your full time job and in addition,
getting several meeting requests per day from
a project team.
These other meetings take a lower priority
and can easily add stress to your day, right?
Well, for each stakeholder, the project is
one entity, so it can look overwhelming to
get so many meeting invites from the team,
it can look like the project team isn't coordinated
using their time well.
Managing stakeholders is a shared responsibility
between the PM and the BA on the project.
So what does successful PM and BA collaboration
look like in the area of stakeholder management?
It means regular touch bases to discuss which
stakeholders you're meeting with and what
the agenda is with them.
At times this entails combining meetings when
both are meeting with the same person in the
same time frame.
Collaborating together on these meetings involves
working together to empathize with wherever
stakeholders at and creating shared key messages
when meeting with them.What does this create?
It creates a shared front in the eyes of a
stakeholder who may need to see this partnership
to trust what you're doing and feel comfortable
contributing some tactical things.
Pat and Bailey discussed about stakeholders
together are things like the role of each
stakeholder and expectations.
Who influences the stakeholder and who do
they influence and what's going on in their
area that may connect with the project or
project stress.
What is the stakeholders current mindset about
the project and the time they're investing
with the team?
Pat and Bailey have found that all of this
helps build better relationships, trust and
engagement.
It also helped them bring stakeholders in
as stakeholders could now see the value of
their time and how it would be used, pat and
Bailey stakeholder before struggled to see
how their time with the project team would
be useful to their full time jobs.
Now they see how working with the team helps
them in other areas as well.
And Pat and Bailey are also very sensitive
to ensure the time is used well to maximize
this Pat and Bailey do this by helping their
stakeholders see and imagine the future, which
impacts everything they work on.