I once heard a PM say that a project manager,
his biggest fear of a business analyst is
scope creep.
I get it.
The PM is concerned that when eliciting requirements,
A BA will agree to stakeholder's requests
for some more scope and the PM schedule and
budgeter that impacted.
As I've grown in my BA career, I've also learned
to appreciate that some scope creep is good
and needed, scope creep happens in many ways,
and no matter how it happens, it needs to
be a collaborative discussion.
Some scope creep is not great for projects
and some is absolutely needed to ensure that
the solution delivers value.
Let's dig into some more.
Pat the PM and Bailey the BA are working hard
on the CRM project with so many impacted groups
as they understand more about what's coming
changes and what's needed are evolving and
being discussed at a furious pace.
Pat and Bailey must find a way to get all
of us under control, they worked together
to define and manage the change process for
when they have changes to requirements.
This is easier when iterations are short and
work in progress is small.
Agile teams experience this with their work.
However, teams that have a larger work in
progress and longer iterations need to manage
change carefully.So what do Pat and Bailey
need to do to manage scope?
Well, they agree on a baseline from which
changes will be managed.
Then, when a potential change comes up, they
agree on how they'll do things like identify
what the changes, discuss if it's feasible,
discuss if it's the right thing to do to get
the outcome the project needs.
Discuss the impact to the quality, scope,
budget and schedule.
And bring options and a decision for the leaders
to make some techniques that help keep all
of us organized.
Are things like a change log and a decision
log to track changes and decisions and a change
intake checklist to make sure Pat and Bailey
have the needed information to further develop
the options and also a traceability matrix
which helps them see which requirements tied
to what outcomes, teams, designs and tests.
Together, Pat and Bailey make change an easy
process for the team and stakeholders, pat
and Bailey trust one another with scope and
changes.
The stakeholders see this and in turn, trust
them to bring the right decisions and options
to leaders.
Scope changes and scope management should
be a positive, not something to fear with
the right mindset and collaboration, the right
scope will become more obvious to everyone.