Business analysts and project managers can
work together as a united front and form an
amazing partnership to enable better project
and business outcomes, the quality of the
requirements, process, tasks and techniques
is only enhanced when we collaboratively work
together.
By leveraging both the PM and BAs skill sets,
we can more effectively deliver value to our
stakeholders and the organization.
This course has described a variety of scenarios
and examples of how we can facilitate and
work together, take advantage of having two
great minds instead of just one.
Also, there are several other courses on this
learning platform that can help you understand
more about the PM and BA rules to gain more
perspective about the role you are working
with, my advice to you set aside time to meet
regularly together to leverage each other's
skill sets and the strong assets each of you
bring to the team.
Share stories and swap learnings from past
projects to determine the best path to take
with your current or upcoming projects.
Project Manager and business analyst collaboration
will bring enhanced value and satisfaction
to your stakeholders.