A
WB US identifies the work needed to complete
a project but it doesn't tell you how long
the work will take or
when it can be performed
To do that you need to turn your list of
tasks into a schedule first put the tasks into
the right sequence you add dependencies or links
to tasks to identify which tasks have to
finish before other tasks can start which
tasks finish at the same time.
And so on. For example the task
build specs has to finish before.
Review specs can start likewise.
Review specs has to finish before approved specs
can start we'll look at dependencies in
detail later in the course.
For now the most common dependency type is finish
to start next you add the time you
estimate each task will take time estimates and
task sequence help determine how long the
entire project will take third you assign the
people on your project team to tasks with
the estimated time and people
assigned to do the work.
You can calculate the task duration.
Finally take into account other constraints
like deadlines and when resources are
00:
available. If your initial schedule doesn't work you
can tweak it in various ways whether
you're trying to shorten the schedule cut
costs or even out people's workloads the
schedule is one of the most
important aspects of your project.
It tells you how long the project will last and
when you need the people who will do the
00:
work.