with most projects money is important
whether you're trying to make it save it
or stay within a budgeted amount
project cost is one of the three key
constraints you need to manage
and the project budget is your starting
point the project budget should be a
realistic estimate of the cost to
complete the project work
if your estimate is unrealistically high
the project could be cancelled if the
estimate is too low
the project will cost more which usually
means
it won't deliver the financial benefit
it's supposed to
you estimate all the costs associated
with completing the project work
including labor materials and other
costs
like travel you can start with rough
estimates for the first few levels of
your work breakdown structure
then create more accurate estimates as
you
learn more about the project labor cost
is
usually a big part of a project's cost
that is what you pay people who work on
the project
if you hire vendors or contractors their
charges go
directly into project labor costs for
employees
you typically use the burdened cost
that includes salary and employee
benefits
you can get burdened rates for roles
from your accounting or
hr department projects might use
other types of time-based resources
think
equipment or office space that you rent
these costs go into your calculations
too then there's material cost
the hospital scheduling project could
include a new
server or training guides and
documentation notebooks
finally be sure to include other types
of costs
that don't fit in the previous three
categories
for example travel training expenses
and fees have you ever gotten
into a cash crunch when you didn't have
enough money on hand to pay expenses
projects can run into cash flow problems
too
which is why you figure out when project
expenses will occur
when you assign resources and other
costs to the tasks in your project
schedule
you'll get a rough idea what your cash
flow looks like
let's say management has money allocated
for the project
like the grants and donations earmarked
for the hospital scheduling project
if your cost estimate is higher than the
allocated amount
you have to look at ways to reduce the
project cost
you might eliminate non-essential
expenses or find
less expensive resources maybe cut scope
in the hospital scheduling project
management
allocated eight hundred and fifty
thousand dollars
the estimate including contingency is
nine hundred and fifty thousand
you might consider working with less
contingency funds
ask for more money or dive in to find
ways to cut the total cost
the project budget is the cost target
you aim for
as you manage a project for practice
think about what you can do about the
hundred thousand dollars
that exceeds the amount that management
has allocated for the scheduling project