You've already put a lot of planning into your
project, the next step is to plan for what
could go wrong because, you know, something
will instead of asking for an adrenaline
rush, why not identify what could go wrong so
you can plan ahead for dealing with issues?
Let's start with risks you're aware of,
they're called known unknowns, things like
weather delays or
resources being unavailable.
Let's look at some examples of things
that can introduce risk to projects.
Technology, it might cost more than you expect, not
work the way it's supposed to or not
show up when you need it.
A widely dispersed project
team can increase risk.
You could have delays due to
time zone differences, miscommunication from different
languages or cultures, or lack of teamwork
because remote team members haven't developed
effective working relationships.
Lack of detail, like specifics on deliverables, due
dates or who will work on your
project can lead to all sorts of problems.
Limited options, like people with rare skills
increase risk because you don't have easy
alternatives to apply if a problem arises.
Work with everyone on your team to identify
risks, you can ask experts for different
parts of the project about the risks they foresee
as key people on the project, what they
think and ask other project managers
about risks from similar projects.
Fill out a risk information form for each risk
you identify, include as much detail as you
00:
can, which objectives are in danger, what events
can cause the risk to occur, what the
00:
consequences are, who owns the
risk, and so on.
Up until now, we've talked about risks we can
anticipate, but what do you do about the
risks you can't predict?
These are called unknown unknowns, they come
from situations that are so unlikely that
they never occur to you the 9/11 attack
was an event that no one thought possible.
You're unlikely to have to deal with such
a significant unknown risk, but you will
encounter unknown risks at some point and
you need to plan for them.
How? By setting aside contingency funds
and time for dealing with them.
The question is, how much
should you set aside?
Many companies use a percentage of the project
budget like 15 percent, but the percentage
is typically based on past experience.
To minimize the effect of risks, you first
have to identify the risks that your project
faces. Try to identify several risks that
the hospital scheduling project might face for
an extra challenge.
Use the risk information form in the
exercise files to document the risks.