a risk management plan documents
which risks you're going to worry about
and how you plan to handle them
first identify which risks warrant
managing start by evaluating how likely
they are and how
serious their impact would be
rate risks by probability and impact
using a scale of one to five where
one is unlikely or not serious
and five is highly likely or extremely
serious
then multiply the probability and impact
to calculate
a risk score it makes sense to manage
risks that are at least
fairly likely and serious that means
you need a plan for any risk with a
score
of nine or more for example
suppose older hospital computers are
very
likely to be incompatible with the new
scheduling systems
new computers increase the budget so the
impact is
very serious the risks score is 25
so you'll definitely need to manage it
risk 1's probability and impact are both
medium
its score is 9 and you need to plan for
it
risk 4 is fairly serious but it isn't
likely
its score is three so you won't plan for
it
next you plan how you'll handle each
risk
the goal of a risk response is to plan
the actions you would take to reduce
adverse consequences a risk might have
on your project
here are some risk responses you can use
the easiest option
is to accept the consequences
that's fine for risks with low
probability and
impact avoiding risk is another approach
for instance changing the project's
scope to remove
the risky part of the project mitigating
risk
means taking steps to reduce the
consequences
or impact of the risk for example
by running a feasibility study you'll
have a better idea
whether a scheduling system will meet
the schedule
budget and other objectives
transferring risk means handing off the
risk to someone else
like when you purchase insurance this
reduces risk
but doesn't eliminate it insurance might
relieve
costs it won't eliminate other factors
like time delays
make sure your responses aren't overkill
if a schedule delay triggers a
500 late fee it doesn't make sense to
spend
five thousand dollars to prevent the
delay
remember contingency time and funds can
be used to handle risks
that have no other response or to handle
risks you didn't identify
up front the final step in a risk
management plan is defining
how to monitor risks and measure
responses
create a risk log to summarize the risks
you'll manage
for each risk include a description of
the risk
the events or circumstances that trigger
the probability and impact the response
you've chosen
who will monitor the risk the result you
expect from the response
if you have to use it and finally the
risk status
keep your risk plan up to date as the
project progresses
some risks become less likely as time
passes
other risks may be introduced because of
project changes
risks occur so you track what caused
them
their impact and whether your responses
are working
a risk management plan helps protect
your project from
things that can go wrong for practice
fill out more of the risk log in the
exercise files