if you've ever heard abbot and
costello's
who's on first skit you know how hard it
can be to get your point across
the success of a project depends on good
communication that's why you set up a
communication
plan the right people getting the right
information at the right time and
in the right way you start with your
audiences
who needs to know about the project the
responsibility matrix
is a good place to look to find your
audiences
second what do your audiences need
or want to know management stakeholders
care about a project
achieving its objectives early on you
give them the project plans so they can
see
how you're going to deliver later on
they want to know about
progress how much you've spent and the
overall project results
the project sponsor is tightly connected
with the project
you'll probably communicate with the
sponsor more often
maybe in face-to-face meetings
functional managers
initially need to know the skill sets
you need
when you need them and other things like
cost
constraints once people are on
assignment
these managers want to know when their
people will be done
team members need to know what they're
supposed to do
they're more likely to buy into the
project if you tell them
how their work fits into the big picture
as time passes they also need to know
what's coming up next
the last part of a communication plan is
the how
how often the methods you use and the
format
face-to-face communication is good for
brainstorming
getting to know people and discussing
sensitive topics
if your team is dispersed geographically
email
conference calls and video conferencing
are indispensable
you know that stakeholder management is
all about
getting and keeping stakeholders support
for your project
the communication plan helps by spelling
out
how you're going to communicate with
stakeholders to keep them on board
and happy a communication plan helps
ensure that
people get the information they need in
the most
effective way to solidify your
understanding
set up a communication plan for the
hospital scheduling project