project success actually means
meeting objectives not exceeding them
quality management includes processes to
make sure that a project
satisfies its objectives and
requirements
a quality management plan is your
roadmap
to meeting objectives project quality
translates into meeting the customers
requirements
and delivering on time and within budget
with deliverables and products quality
also means conforming to specifications
a quality management plan has three
components
first there's the quality standards for
deliverables
for a product the quality standard might
include the acceptable
tolerance for its dimensions or the
acceptable number of
defective widgets in a batch for the
hospital scheduling project
one quality standard might be that the
scheduling system
meets all the required scheduling
functions
keep in mind that the goal is to meet
the quality standards
obviously you don't want quality that's
below standard
the customer won't be happy they might
ask for additional work to get it right
or simply refuse to pay
this might surprise you you don't want
quality that's
higher than required why because other
aspects of the project can suffer
like a later finish date or higher cost
the second part of the quality
management plan is a
quality assurance plan this spells out
the processes you use
during the project to ensure that the
final results
meet the quality standards for the
scheduling system
reviewing requirements and designs falls
into this category
you might also test software functions
as they're developed
finally you plan for quality control
which means how you measure and monitor
quality in the final deliverables
the bottom line is that you examine or
measure results to see if they
meet the standard set for the scheduling
project
the final acceptance test would measure
whether the processes and
system achieve their objectives for the
hospital's new cancer wing
you would do a walk through to confirm
that the construction has been completed
correctly
continuous improvement is a big part of
quality management if you find quality
issues
you analyze the problems to see how to
prevent them
or at least reduce their frequency cause
and effect diagrams
are also called fishbone diagrams
because they
look like a fish skeleton they help
identify factors that could lead to
problems
those factors can help you figure out
ways to prevent the problems
another tool is a pareto diagram this
shows
how many defects are generated by each
cause
that way you can address the causes that
produce the most defects
first by developing a quality management
plan
you can ensure that your project meets
its quality objectives
for practice identify potential quality
assurance processes
and quality control measures for each of
the project
objectives