the government tax code started out so
simple
but a deduction here a new rule there
and now we have the complicated tax
returns of today
you know changes are going to happen so
the only solution is to manage them
a change management plan helps you add
important changes
into your project while keeping out the
ones that don't make sense
first you identify what you want to
control
like the project's scope requirements
and the schedule
or perhaps the entire project plan the
versions you control
are called baseline documents
the list of project requirements
approved by the stakeholders
is your baseline if new requirements are
suggested
you use your change management process
to decide
whether or not to add them to the
requirements list
you also need a group that reviews
change requests and decides whether to
approve them
it's called the change review board and
it's usually made up of
key stakeholders then you define
a change management process that's
what will happen when someone requests a
change
the process your organization chooses
depends on things like the company
culture
and project size here are the typical
components
of change management processes the first
process
is documenting and submitting a change
request
use a standardized change request form
that requesters fill out
it's easier to evaluate changes because
each request has the
information the review board needs to
make decisions
include details about the requested
change
the reason it's needed the business
justification
and the results it should produce
next someone has to evaluate the request
and estimate its impact
as project manager you can assign this
task to
someone on your team the evaluator
determines
whether the change is needed if it is
the person evaluates whether the
suggested approach is correct
or if an alternative would be better
the evaluator estimates the effort and
costs the change would require
the impact on the project and whether it
introduces
risks third the change review board
reviews evaluated change requests the
board might accept or reject the change
request
they also might ask for more detail or
revisions
be sure to communicate the decision to
the person who requested the change
for approved requests you update the
baseline documents to reflect the change
for example your project schedule might
need new tasks
or deadlines extended finally
track where change requests are in your
process a change request log
shows the status of submitted change
requests
who's in charge of the request the
impact estimate
current status and at the end actual
impact consider setting
thresholds so team leads can decide what
to do with smaller requests
that way your change management process
isn't overwhelmed with small
items also create a process for
emergency changes that need a rapid
decision
between meetings of the change review
board
a change management plan helps you
include changes that make sense in your
project
while protecting your project from being
overwhelmed with
unnecessary changes to solidify
your understanding of change management
draw a flowchart of the change
management processes the hospital
might use