Even with homemade chicken soup, you
don't make everything from scratch.
Imagine how long it would take and how much it
would cost if you had to raise your own
chickens, vegetable and wheat and
make chicken stock and noodles.
The same goes in the project world.
Procuring products, services and skills can be a
lot quicker than trying to do everything
yourself. When you purchase items from outside
your organization, you need to plan how
you're going to do that. You guessed it.
That's what a procurement plan is for.
First, you identify what
you need to purchase.
Maybe you need people with specific skills or
you need more people than your organization
has, or the project
requires products and materials.
Second, you document
your procurement processes.
Who handles procurement?
Is it the purchasing department, the project
team or a combination of the two?
The plan describes criteria for choosing
vendors, the selection process, types of
contracts you use and how
you manage those contracts.
Fortunately, you usually don't have
to invent all these processes.
Most organizations already have
procurement processes in place.
Talk to your purchasing department or finance
group to find out how it's done.
Third, you describe your make or buy decision
process, basically how you decide whether to
use in-house products or
services or procure them.
To make an informed make or buy
decision, it's important to understand your needs.
Make sure your requirements are
clear and then prioritize them.
That way, it's easier to pick
products that meet your requirements.
Plus, you can resist bells
and whistles you don't need.
You have to see if a product that meets
your needs is available, if it is, evaluate how
it matches up with your requirements.
Before you finalize your decision, consider the pros
and cons of making versus buying if
your project is on a tight timeline,
buying is probably the right choice.
The last part of the procurement plan is a
list of potential vendors who offer what you
need to purchase. Describe how you researched
vendors and contractors and the criteria
for developing the list.
Procurement planning helps you make smart
decisions about whether to purchase products
and services, and if you do, which products
and services to procure as an exercise,
identify some of the criteria you might
use to choose the scheduling system vendor.