For initiating and planning, you might work with
a small core team before you begin
executing project work, you bring on the rest
of the team and acquire needed equipment
and materials. If team members come from
within your organization, procurement might be
as simple as telling your in-house team
it's time to start your assignments.
For resources outside your organization, the procurement
process has a few more steps
solicitation, evaluation, selection, contracting
and ongoing management.
These steps can take time, so be sure to
leave room in your schedule for performing them.
Solicitation often begins with a request
for proposal abbreviated as RFP.
It's a typical way to ask
vendors for proposals or bids.
An RFP describes the services or resources
you need when you need them.
And your budget for the work include the criteria
you plan to use to select a vendor so
companies can decide whether or not to bid.
Don't forget to include instructions and the
deadline for submitting a proposal and the
date you'll announce your decision.
Once you have all the vendors, proposals or
bids, you hunker down and evaluate the
responses using your criteria, how you select
the winner depends on the size and
complexity of the project.
Evaluation and selection might be as easy as
filling in a spreadsheet with ratings and
choosing the vendor with the highest score.
For large jobs, you might whittle the submissions down
to a short list of vendors and ask
each one in the second round to prepare
a more detailed presentation or demonstrate what
they have to offer.
For example, in the scheduling system project, you
might ask the top two candidates to
demonstrate their systems and show
how features satisfy project requirements.
Contracting is when you prepare and sign
a contract for the resources you need.
Contracts usually include a statement of
work terms and conditions, deliverables,
deadlines and, of course, the price.
Contracts fall into several categories, fixed price
contracts work when your project is
well defined, this type of contract places the
risk on the vendor because the vendor is
paid a fixed amount, no matter how much time
the work takes or how much it costs.
Time and materials contracts pay for
time worked and expenses incurred.
The project accepts most of the risk.
So it's common to include and not
to exceed value to limit the price.
A cost plus contract is like time and
materials with the addition of penalties or rewards
based on the vendors performance.
With a retainer, you agree to pay for a
specified amount of time and define the work as
you go. Complete procurement steps early enough,
so the resources you need are available
00:
when work begins.
For example, if your project requires materials
with long lead times, you'll need to
start procurement early.
After you award contracts, you don't sit back
and relax while project work is underway.
You manage those contracts, monitor the vendor
performance and manage any changes for
practice. Think about which type of contract you
would use for the scheduling system and
why.