now that you have a plan for the project
you need to get the stakeholders to
approve the plan so you can start work
getting approval is important because
you need the stakeholders commitment to
make the project
a success you might think about getting
approval by
mailing or emailing a packet to
stakeholders and asking them to sign on
the dotted line
i don't recommend that approach here's
the problem
people probably won't read through the
plan sure they might sign their names
but later if they find something they
disagree with
their commitment disappears and you end
up back to planning
a face-to-face sign-off meeting is more
effective
schedule a meeting specifically for
getting approval
the agenda is straightforward
first present the project plan to make
sure that the stakeholders
agree with it if issues arise
deal with them right then and there
or if the issues are big enough you
might have to reschedule the sign off
so you can rework the plan once everyone
agrees
ask them all to sign a signature page to
indicate their approval
if you can't get everyone in the same
room a video conference or conference
call works too
ask the people in other locations to
transmit their signatures to you by
fax email or even snail mail
signing a project plan isn't like
signing a legal document
you're never going to go back to your
stakeholders and say but you
signed this what's important
is that the stakeholders understand what
the project is about
and buy into it