[Music]
at this point in the hospital scheduling
project
you've created drafts of several
planning documents
but in the project world things change
and this project
is no exception the government has
launched a major initiative
in cancer research part of this
initiative is
using a common scheduling tool for all
cancer treatment facilities
brisland hospital's new cancer ward will
have to use the government scheduling
tool
instead of the solution that your
project will implement for the rest of
the hospital
in the exercise files there's a change
request submitted by the project manager
and approved by the project customer
this
change means that you'll have to revise
some planning documents
for this challenge take 20 to 30 minutes
to identify
which planning documents you need to
revise
and at a high level what you would
change
after you work through your solution
look at the files
i would revise in response to this
request