a big part of building a schedule is
getting tasks in the right order
meal time goes a lot better when you
cook dinner
before you eat it by putting tasks in
order
you turn your wbs into a sequence that
defines
when project work should occur
in the project management world network
diagram
is the name for the diagram that shows
the sequence of tasks
each task appears in a box with the task
name
and perhaps other task info arrows drawn
between boxes
shows how the tasks are linked
even if you build the sequence by
putting sticky notes up on a whiteboard
you're creating a network diagram
the links between tasks aren't just
about
which task starts first a task
dependency
is when one task controls the timing of
another
the task in control is called a
predecessor
and the one being controlled is the
successor
each task has a start and finish so
there are
four types of task dependencies
finish to start dependencies are the
most common
the finish of one task controls when the
other task starts
for example you have to analyze the
current scheduling processes
before you can start designing new ones
a finish to finish dependency means the
finish of one task
controls the finish of the other for
example
the dev team finishing the scheduling
features
controls when they finish testing the
with a small delay to test those last
bits of customization
start to start means that the start of
one activity
triggers the start of the other this
dependency type
can cause trouble if the predecessor
takes longer than it's supposed to
as shown here if writing takes longer
the reviewing task looks like it
finishes before writing does
that would mean either some writing
isn't reviewed
or the reviewers have to wait until the
writing is done
in this example the correct logic is
actually
finish to finish with a finish to finish
dependency
if the writing finish date is delayed so
is the finished date
for reviewing an example of a
true start to start dependency is
pouring concrete and
troweling it because concrete hardens
with time
the start of pouring concrete controls
when traveling starts start to finish
dependencies
don't occur very often that's a good
thing because they can be confusing
the start of one task triggers the
finish of another
so the task and control occurs after the
one it controls
consider the shifts at a retail store
the first shift
can't finish until the clerk for the
second shift
shows up you can figure out which type
of dependency to use by asking a few
questions
which task controls the other
that tells you which task is the
predecessor
does the start or finish date of the
first task control
the second task that identifies whether
the dependency begins with start or
finish
does the predecessor control the start
or finish
of the successor that identifies whether
the second
half of the dependency is start or
finish
adding task dependencies to your tasks
in a network diagram
gets your project tasks into sequence
now that you know all the dependency
types build a network diagram for the
tasks
in the partial wbs in the exercise files