your project tasks are in sequence
and you've estimated their durations the
final piece of your scheduling puzzle
is how many people work on each task and
when they're available
with that info you can see how long
tasks take
and when they should occur you assign
resources only to work packages
the lowest levels in your wbs because
they represent
work that must be done summary tasks
roll up work from lower levels so you
don't assign resources to these tasks
milestones don't have duration so it
doesn't make sense to assign resources
to them either
what happens when you assign resources
to work packages
depends on whether you estimate task
duration
or work let's say you estimate duration
and assign the number of resources
you expect to get your scheduling tool
will calculate the work
those resources can perform in that
duration
let's say you're expecting two vendor
resources
full time to design scheduling features
the task duration estimate is two weeks
two people
working full time for two weeks is 160
hours
on the other hand if you estimate work
your scheduling tool
uses the work estimate and the resource
allocation
to calculate the task duration
some tasks don't get shorter no matter
how many people you assign meetings
are the classic example a four-hour
meeting is
four hours long whether three people
attend or
ten when resources are available also
affects
when work occurs for example your
schedule
might show the equipment installation
starting on november 9th
if your it folks are wrapping up another
installation
and the team won't be available until
november 18th
guess what you have to delay that task
in your schedule
to when the resources are available
don't forget to assign other types of
resources you need
like materials equipment and ancillary
costs
with all resources assigned you finally
get a good idea
what the schedule looks like to practice
work through the assignment exercise in
the exercise files