Milestones get their name from the past when people
placed stones by the side of a road to
mark each mile in projects, milestones do a
similar job, but they show progress and other
key project points rather than distance.
They show when you've completed key tasks or portions
of a project, and they make it easy
to see how much you've
completed and when it finished.
Milestones are great as the first and last
tasks in your project schedule, by starting a
project with a milestone, you can reschedule the
project start date just by moving the
00:
starting milestone to a later date.
By looking at the final milestone, you can tell
whether the project is on time, late or
ahead of schedule. Milestones also help highlight
progress you've made in between the
projects start and finish when all the work
leading up to that milestone is done, you
have the satisfaction of marking
off another milestone as complete.
If you're waiting for someone to deliver something
at a milestone to flag that delivery,
finally use a milestone to flag decisions that
determine what happens next in a project
or use a milestone for an approval that
determines when the work after the approval can
start. Milestone's help indicate progress in a project
when you link them to work tasks.
You can also use them to reschedule
portions of a project for practice.
Add Milestone's to the network
diagram in the exercise files.