it's important to make your project
schedule
realistic so tasks occur as close as
possible to the dates you planned
one way to build reality into your
schedule is to estimate
task duration based on the hours people
work
on the project each day people don't
a hundred percent of their time on
project tasks people don't even work a
hundred percent of every workday
things like staff meetings paperwork
training
and time off chew up work hours
even walking across campus uses up work
time
so do your best to estimate the number
of hours
people typically work another dose of
reality
is adjusting estimated task hours based
on how fast the assigned workers are
for example if someone is a whiz at
getting computers connected to the
network
you can change the task work hours to
reflect her productivity
third to keep people productive assign
resources to work on no more than
three tasks at a time switching between
tasks
means a person has to switch focus and
that
introduces a small delay each time
when resources are in demand and you
have to assign them to several tasks
adjust those assignments to reflect
their decreased productivity
when you make adjustments like these add
a note to your schedule
to document the change and the reason
why
that way you'll know what to do if other
changes come up in the future
the closer you model your resource
assignments to reality
the easier it will be to keep your
project on time
complete the assignment exercise in the
exercise files
to practice assigning resources to tasks