the critical path is the longest
sequence of tasks
in your schedule why is the critical
path
so critical because any delay on that
delays the finish date of the project
just as important if you can figure out
how to shorten the critical path
you can shorten the project schedule how
do you tell
which tasks are on the critical path
simple
they don't have any slack also known as
float just like a string with no slack
critical tasks can't move without
affecting the project finish date
in this simple example the system and
training tasks
occur one after the other with no slack
if any of these tasks are delayed the
project finish date moves later in time
on the other hand if a task has slack
like the reports task here it can start
later without
delaying the tasks that come after it
the reports task could delay by a few
weeks before it delays the project
finish
let's look at how you tell whether or
not a task has slack
a task has two sets of start and finish
dates
the early start and early finish are the
earliest possible dates the tasks can
start or finish
based on its dependencies with other
tasks
you calculate these with what's called
a forward pass that's where you start at
the project start date
and use task durations and dependencies
to calculate
when they finish for example
the reports task can start as early as
october 26th
and finish on november 27th
the late start and late finish are the
latest possible dates
without delaying tasks that follow
you calculate these dates by working
backwards from the end of the project
you got it the backward pass
the late finish for the reports task is
december 18th
so working backwards the late start is
november 16th
the task has several weeks of slack so
it isn't
on the critical path critical tasks have
no slack in other words the early and
late dates are the same
that's why the training task is on the
critical path
the good news you don't have to perform
these calculations
when you use project scheduling programs
they calculate the critical path
for you the critical path
is the place to look when you want to
keep your project
on time or deliver it early
to test your understanding calculate the
late dates for the tasks in the exercise
and use them to identify the critical
path