critical chain is a slightly different
take on the critical path
it can help you deliver your project
earlier than you would otherwise
and helps prevent delays in the project
finish date
the critical chain approach schedules
tasks to occur
as late as possible one benefit of doing
this
is that you don't spend money on the
project until you absolutely have to
if you have to adjust the schedule you
move tasks to occur
earlier criticalchain also focuses on
resource limitations to identify the
important tasks to manage
that's because resource constraints are
often the toughest ones to deal with
you start by scheduling tasks with the
most
limited resources so you use those
people as effectively as possible
it's like filling a bucket to the brim
by putting the biggest rocks in a bucket
first
followed by smaller rocks and finishing
up with sand
the critical chain approach uses buffers
to give a project breathing room that
way
delays aren't as likely to delay the
finish date
what do these buffers do they're like
adding
shared time to the project each task
doesn't get its own time buffer
instead sequences of tasks
share a buffer that way only the tasks
that actually need extra time
use some of the buffer you apply a
couple of different types of buffers
first you tack buffers onto the end
of each sequence of tasks then you add a
project buffer at the end of the project
to protect the overall project finish
date
the critical chain approach helps
deliver projects on time
or earlier than planned for practice
go ahead and add buffers to the portion
of the project
provided in the exercise files