stakeholders can be an impatient bunch
you estimate when the project will
finish and more often than not
they ask if you can deliver it sooner or
maybe your project gets delayed and you
need to make up time
let's look at a few techniques for
shortening the project schedule
fast tracking means you overlap tasks
that
normally occur one after the other
let's say you want to finish design more
quickly
you can have some folks start designing
software features before the system
design
is complete fast tracking is simple
you just add an overlap to two tasks
with finish to start dependencies
the best tasks to fast track are the
longest tasks on the critical path
remember you shorten the whole project
when you shorten the critical path
fast tracking the longest tasks on the
critical path
shortens the schedule and also
introduces the fewest number of risks
and changes
which brings us to the disadvantage of
fast tracking
it increases risk for example
changes to the system design could
result in
redoing work on the software design
the second technique crashing means you
spend additional money to shorten the
schedule
like paying for more people or expedited
delivery of key materials
the critical path is still the place to
look for tasks to crash
think about it why would you spend money
to shorten tasks if they aren't going to
shorten your schedule
you also want the alternative that
shortens the schedule the amount you
need
for the least amount of money start with
the least
expensive tasks to crash and move on to
tasks with higher price tags
remember you crash tasks only until
you've shortened the schedule by the
amount you need
a crash table makes it easy to see which
tasks to crash
it shows the cost to crash each critical
task
and the duration you eliminate by
crashing them
choose the tasks with the lowest crash
cost
per week if they have the same crash
cost per week
crash the longer ones first that way you
crash the fewest tasks
you can take crashing only so far
at some point adding more people won't
shorten the duration
because people start getting in each
other's way and on each other's nerves
new people take time to get up to speed
and they can slow down
existing team members who have to help
them get oriented
keep in mind you review the critical
path
after every adjustment an adjustment
could change the critical path you want
to make sure
the next task you work on is still on it
the third method for shortening a
schedule is to cut
project scope if the tasks for deleted
scope are on the critical path
cutting scope shortens the schedule
fast tracking crashing and cutting scope
help shorten the project schedule each
has its pros and cons
so choose the method that makes the most
sense for the project at hand
look at the schedule in the exercise
files what techniques would you use to
shorten the scheduling project
and which tasks might be involved