once the stakeholders have approved the
project plan
it's time to define your project
baseline
the baseline is a collection of the
approved project documents
like requirements the schedule budget
spreadsheets and more basically
everything you want to control
with change management process with
baseline documents
you can compare actual project
performance to the baseline
to see how the project's doing because
the baseline is controlled by the change
management process
any changes to baseline documents show
up as
change requests how you define the
baseline
depends on what you're defining first
save the baseline version of plan
documents
if something changes you flag those
changes in a revision of the
corresponding baseline document
next baseline the values in your project
schedule
project scheduling programs typically
provide a feature for saving a baseline
the baseline includes the approved
values for start and finish dates
task duration work cost and so on
as you record progress or make changes
to the schedule
the program will show any variances from
the baseline
once you document the project baseline
you're ready to use it to evaluate
progress and project performance for
practice
what documents would you include in the
scheduling project baseline
and where might you store these
documents to make them
easy to access