[Music]
in this challenge
tension is increasing between your
project team
and the vendor team members who supply
expertise
on the cancer wards scheduling system
the friction
seems to be the cause of the vendor team
missing the deadline
for delivering specifications for the
connection between the two scheduling
systems
this missed deadline will impact your
project deadline
because there is almost no slack in this
part of your schedule
you need to intervene what actions
should you take
to address this team relationship
problem
take about 10 minutes to think about it
after you plan your response look at my
take on resolving this
issue