hey guys next i'm going to show you a
real life example
of an agile kanban board for one of my
projects and this is a real-life project
that i worked on
a couple of months ago in this example
you're going to see that we had each
team member
with their own set of user stories so we
had the work in progress what we called
in the project in the work in progress
which is basically the same as doing
when we do an agile board and we create
a column called doing
in this case we called it work in
progress and then we had the done at the
end
of the kanban board which is something
that you also have so generally when you
create a kanban board
you have the to-do doing sometimes you
have qa
and and then done whether you have the
qa or not is optional it's up to you as
a team
sometimes some agile projects would just
or some agile teams would just
do it as part of their user story
perform the qa
within the user story and then when they
complete the user story
they would move it to the done so in
this case
because we were working on a project
that was a huge massive project
and because it was so big and it had so
many different streams of work
you had to set up the agile kanban work
a little bit different than what you
normally would
but the beauty of this is i can show you
how you can adapt agile kanban work
to your real life scenario so like i've
said many times before
agile is very flexible you don't have to
play everything by the book you have to
learn and take
what is the best that you can find and
adapt it and adjust it to your real life
project or scenario in our particular
case like you're going to see in a
moment
because our backlog was so big and we
had so many things in the to do
we actually separated that in our trello
in a separate board
to our work in progress and our
completion
and even when we were completing the
work we would move the sprints
to a separate list just because we had
so many sprints we were working on right
so we were working on
monthly sprints in this case and we did
that just to make it
easier for us as a team to control the
timing and the work that we were doing
so basically we set up each sprint
exactly
as per the calendar month of each month
so
basically we're talking about four-week
sprints right and in our case
in this particular project that made a
lot more sense for us
because we're working on huge
initiatives and we needed a little bit
more time to complete
our sprints as you already know you
don't have to do four-week sprints
generally sprints are two weeks but some
agile teams do three or four
it's entirely up to the agile team and
to their particular scenario to decide
which sprint duration works best for
them like i said in our example
we chose four weeks because we're
working a massive massive project
over multiple sprints multiple streams
of work
multiple stakeholders and different
areas of the business
so this particular adaptation of the
kanban board to our particular business
need
made a lot of sense for us and it worked
quite well
as you'll see in the example we had all
the user stories
each team member was working on we had
our
done our completed sprint list of user
stories
and we had a separate backlog and a
separate
list of everything that we had completed
for all of our previous sprints
so it worked really well for us because
we could reference the work
back really easily we could also assign
story points we could also look at our
velocity and how we're progressing
and this also helped us when we're doing
our retrospectives and looking
at what we had accomplished and how we
had done
in that particular sprint so without
further ado let me take you right now to
the example we just discussed
and you'll be able to identify and see
their
real life examples of what we've learned
so far in the course
i hope you enjoy it and i hope you make
the best of it cheers
[Music]
so
you